bankofthewest.com 2007-06-07

# Bank of the West | About Us | Privacy Policy

We recognize your right to privacy. We're pleased you have chosen to bank with us, and we are committed to honor our relationship using great care to responsibly protect the information you share with us. 

* * *

Our customer information privacy policy, detailed in this statement, serves as the standard for all Bank of the West employees in the collection, use, sharing, retention, and security of individual customer information.

Without compromising your privacy, we also wish to offer you, from time to time, superior financial products and services that we believe can help you achieve your financial objectives. We believe we can do this by observing our policy.

**Expectation of Privacy**

Safekeeping of customer information is a high priority at Bank of the West. We will continue to maintain the high standards necessary to ensure that your information is kept private and secure at all times.

If you close your account(s) or become an inactive customer, we will continue to adhere to this privacy policy.

## Maintenance of Accuracy

We strive to maintain complete and accurate information about you and your accounts. Should you believe that our records contain inaccurate or incomplete information about you, please notify us at the telephone number listed in the "Where to Call" section at the end of this statement. We will correct any inaccuracies.

## Bank of the West Information Management Practices

Information about customers is accumulated from a variety of sources. You provide some information. We record other information, such as your account history, and still other information is obtained from outside sources, such as affiliates and credit reporting agencies.

We limit the collection and use of information about customers to the data necessary to administer our business, provide superior service and offer opportunities we believe may benefit our customers.

We use some information to help identify and mitigate potential risks or loss to the Bank. We also use customer information to identify a likely interest in particular products or services. We use this information only in accordance with our policy.  

## Limitation of Employee Access

Bank employee access to information about individual customers is limited to those with a business reason to have such access. Employees are made aware of the Bank’s privacy policy and trained in procedures that maintain confidentiality. Employees who violate provisions of the privacy policy are subject to disciplinary action.

## Information Security Protection

Bank of the West safeguards information about you according to established security procedures designed to prevent unauthorized access. We continually assess new information protection technology.

## Types of Personal Information Collected

In conducting business at Bank of the West, we collect and maintain various types of information about our customers, including:

  * Identification information (account numbers, Social Security numbers, dates of birth, addresses, and PIN codes);
  * Information regarding your credit worthiness and credit capacity (financial statements, employment information, credit history, and income and expenses);
  * Data we obtain when we verify information in a loan application (such as open lines of credit or deposit accounts);
  * Medical information included in an application for credit insurance;
  * Account activity information (loan or deposit balances and transaction histories); and
  * Information regarding your financial situation that allows us to recommend our products and services, such as investment products offered through BancWest Investment Services.

Bank of the West uses this personal information only for business purposes consistent with ethical banking practices and in compliance with applicable laws and regulations. We may share all of the information that we collect..  

## Information Use by the Bank

The Bank may use your personal information as follows:

Within Bank of the West and Affiliated Companies:

  * As a security measure, to prevent unauthorized persons from accessing your accounts.
  * To conduct business safely and soundly. We use personal information, for example, taken from loan applications to manage risk and ensure that we are prudent underwriters.
  * We may share information about our experience and transactions with you among the Bank's family of companies (BancWest Corporation and its affiliates including First Hawaiian Bank) as permitted by law. We may also share the other types of personal information we collect within the Bank's family of companies.
  * In satisfying legal requirements, such as for tax reporting, as required by state and federal government.
  * In determining which products and services may best serve your needs. Some of these services such as mortgage loan servicing, or products such as credit cards, may be offered through our affiliates.
  * We do not share medical or health information among our family of companies or with other third parties except to process transactions or to provide services you have requested.

With Unaffiliated Third Parties:

Bank of the West does not reveal customer account information or provide other personally identifiable information to unaffiliated companies for their independent use.

We may disclose all of the information we collect, as described in "Types of Personal Information Collected" to companies that perform marketing services on our behalf or to other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements.

As Permitted by Law:

Banks may legally share customer account information or other personally identifiable information with unaffiliated companies when:

  * They assist by contract in providing Bank products and services, e.g., check printers and credit insurance.
  * Information sharing is in the normal course of business, e.g., with credit reporting agencies.
  * The law requires Bank cooperation, e.g., fraud investigation, subpoena, or a request by an authorized government regulator.
  * "Due diligence" is performed during a merger, acquisition or sale of a loan/lease portfolio.
  * A customer has earlier been informed of the possible disclosure of information for marketing or similar purposes and given an opportunity to decline ("opt out").

## Customer Privacy in Third Party Relationships

When we provide customer information to a third party, as permitted by law, we insist—through a written agreement—that the third party maintain the confidentiality of that information..  

## Marketing of Bank of the West's Products and Services

From time to time, the Bank may promote its products and services directly to customers. If you do not want to receive these offers, you may ask the Bank not to include you by following the "opt-out" procedures below.

## Ways to Limit the Bank's Use or Disclosure of Your Personal Information

We, at Bank of the West, have developed this policy statement because we want you to understand and trust our commitment to confidentiality and to further understand how we use personally identifiable information. If you have questions about the privacy of your information, please call us at the telephone number listed in the "Where to Call" section at the end of this statement.

We will provide one privacy policy brochure in the event of joint account relationships. One party may opt-out on behalf of all joint account holders. Once your request for an "opt-out" has been processed, it will remain in effect for the life of the account.

## Opt-Out Procedures

To instruct the Bank not to:

  * provide nonpublic personal information about you to unaffiliated companies offering products and/or services,
  * share information from your applications or outside sources among our family of companies, or
  * provide information to you about the Bank's products and services,

Contact us at the number listed in the "Where to Call" section below.

Please allow us up to 6 weeks for your opt-out to become effective.

**Where to Call**

For questions about our privacy policy or to make an opt-out request, please contact us at (800) 676-BEAR (2327), or if you live outside of the US and Canada, please call collect to (925) 975-3202. To report inaccuracies about your information, please contact us at (800) 488-BANK (2265).

Bank of the West reserves the right to amend this privacy policy at any time. You will be given prior notice of any change.

## Frequently Asked Questions

**How Bank of the West Protects your Privacy**

At Bank of the West, trust is the basis of each customer relationship. We recognize your right to privacy. Our employees treat information concerning your accounts in the same responsible, confidential way we want our own financial affairs treated.

**These Frequently Asked Questions explain:**

How we protect your privacy when you visit the Bank of the West Website

Summary of Our Privacy Policy

Why we have information about you and how we control it

How you can make sure credit reports about you are accurate

How we use information about you outside of the bank

How you can prevent confidential financial information about you from being used fraudulently by others.

**Internet Privacy**

**Is my privacy protected if I visit Bank of the West's Website (www.bankofthewest.com) on the Internet?**

Yes. If you apply online for Bank of the West Bank products, the personal information you provide to us is encrypted using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

Also, if you visit our Web page, our Web server automatically recognizes only:

  * Your Internet Service Provider, but not your specific e-mail address. For instance, if your e-mail address is "johndoe@aol.com," only the aol.com part of the address is recognized.
  * Aggregate information on which pages consumers visit, but no specific information on the individual consumer. The aggregate information we collect (for instance, how many "hits" on a particular Web page) is used for internal review to improve the content of our Web page and is then destroyed.

**What do you do with information that I volunteer, such as survey information or information requests?**

When you request information about a specific product or service, we will use the e-mail address, the postal address or the telephone number only to deliver the requested information.

If you enroll in our eTime Banker® service and supply us with personal data (such as e-mail address, birth date, income range or home ownership information), we may use this data to provide you with personalized information on products, services, or special promotions we feel will be of interest to you. However, if you wish to be excluded from receiving such information by e-mail, we'll give you an opportunity to tell us this online. We will respect your wishes not to receive such e-mail.

**Summary of the Bank of the West Privacy Policy**

**What are the basic elements of your Privacy Policy?**

We recognize the importance you place on your privacy and the confidentiality of your financial information. We want you to be informed of our policies to safeguard your privacy:

(1) We do all that we can to make sure that information we have about customers is accurate and is accessible only by those employees actively engaged in dealing with you or your accounts.

(2) Other than the limited exceptions explained in the Privacy Policy, we do not share confidential customer information outside the Bank of the West family of companies.

(3) We educate our employees about their responsibility to protect your privacy.

**How can I insure that you will not share information about me in the future?**

If you do not want us to share your personal information, and if we choose to participate in any programs in the future, simply contact us as directed in the Where to Call section of the Privacy Policy.

**If I've already signed an "opt-out" form or opted-out through the 800 line, do I need to take further action to insure the privacy of my information?**

No. Your opt-out direction remains in place as long as your account is open.

**I have opened a new account with Bank of the West since I "opted-out." Do I need to opt-out on my new product or service?**

We attempt to apply your opt-out direction to all of your accounts at Bank of the West, to all joint account holders on those accounts, and to any new accounts you open, whenever possible. However, if the account on which you originally opted out has been closed, or if your name or address or other parties on your new account have changed, it may not be possible to match your old account and opt-out direction to your new account. Contact us as directed.

**Are there any conditions under which you will share my non-public personal information?**

There are a few, all of which are allowed under the federal privacy regulation. They are:

(1) when it is required to complete a service you've requested, such as check printing (In these cases, Bank of the West has contracts with vendors that contain provisions that meet our stringent standards for protecting our customers' privacy), 

(2) when we are required to by law or regulation, such as a subpoena or a large cash transaction, and

(3) when any of the signers on the account gives us permission to do so.

**Does this mean you will stop sending me junk mail?**

If you have chosen to opt-out, we will attempt to exclude you and other account holders in your household from our internal mailing and phone solicitation lists whenever possible. However, it is not possible to exclude any account holders from receiving "statement stuffers" and similar types of materials.

You should also be aware that Bank of the West is required to send you certain important types of information, such as change in terms notices, which might appear to be "junk mail" but actually isn't.

**I received several copies of your privacy policy disclosure. Why?**

If all of your accounts at Bank of the West are "linked" (i.e., all your accounts appear on one statement), you should receive only one copy of our privacy policy. However, if you have multiple accounts or receive multiple statements, you may receive a copy of our privacy policy in connection with each account.

**Our Information About You**

**Inside Bank of the West Bank, how do you control information about my accounts?**

Bank of the West's employees are informed of their responsibility to protect the confidentiality of customer information and are subject to disciplinary action for violating this policy. Only employees actively engaged in the discharge of assigned duties involving customer information are authorized to access that information.

**Why do you have information about me?**

We collect and use information about individual customers only:

(1) To open and administer your accounts and provide superior service,

(2) To help us provide you with additional products or services you might want to know about (Many people have told us they like getting information related to their interests or alerting them to unique products and services.), and

(3) To help us protect you and Bank of the West from financial loss.

In some cases, laws governing financial institutions require us to gather information. For example, federal regulations require that we obtain a Social Security Number or Tax Identification Number for most types of accounts.

**What can I do if I discover that information Bank of the West has is inaccurate?**

It's in your interest and ours to have accurate, current, and complete information concerning you and your accounts. If you believe that we have erroneous information, please contact your Bank of the West Branch or call (800) 488-2265. We want to correct any inaccuracies right away.

**Credit Report Information About You**

**Do you use information from consumer credit reports provided from outside the bank?**

Yes. It's standard banking industry practice to obtain information from reputable credit information reporting agencies. When we do, you are protected both by our own Privacy Policy and by the Fair Credit Reporting Act, a federal law.

**What exactly is on these credit reports?**

Your credit report includes personal and financial information such as your account balances and your payment history for credit cards, mortgages or other consumer loans. If you don't make payments on time or miss a payment, your credit report may show that, even if you catch up on your payments later. Late payments and other "negative" information can remain on your credit report for up to 7 years; bankruptcies, for up to 10 years.

If you want to see what information is on your credit report, you may call or write the credit reporting agencies and request a copy of your report. There is a fee for this service. However, if you have been denied credit within the past 60 days because of information in your credit report, you are entitled to a free copy of that report.

If you find a problem, promptly inform the credit bureau in writing. The bureau must investigate the disputed entry and correct any errors. It's a good idea to let each of the major bureaus know if you find a problem in one report.

Here is how to contact three of the larger national credit bureaus:

Equifax, Inc  
P.O. Box 740241  
Atlanta, GA 30374-0241  
(800) 685-1111  

Trans Union Corporation  
P.O. Box 2000  
Chester, PA 19022  
(800) 888-4213  

Experian  
P.O. Box 2002  
Allen, TX 75013-2104  
(888) 397-3742  

**Does Bank of the West provide credit information to credit reporting agencies?**

Yes. In accordance with standard banking industry practice, we share certain information about our customers with reputable credit reporting agencies so creditors can verify the existence and condition of customers' accounts.

On occasion, an entity other than a credit-reporting agency—such as another financial institution or a business—may ask us for credit information about an individual or business customer. For example, you may be applying for a loan at another bank or establishing a credit relationship with a business. In such instances, we will not provide information about you unless you have given your prior written authorization.

**Use of Information About You Outside Bank of the West**

**Do you give information about customers to the government?**

We only disclose customer information to the government,

(1) when we are required to do so by laws and regulations, 

(2) when we are served with a subpoena or court or administrative order, or

(3) when a customer authorizes us to do so.

**What happens if I'm involved in a lawsuit and bank records are subpoenaed?**

If you are involved in a lawsuit, we will only disclose information about you or your accounts to third-party litigants when we are required to do so during a court proceeding.

**Do you give information about me to anyone else outside Bank of the West's family of companies?**

Like most banks, Bank of the West contracts with outside companies to provide support services such as data processing, check printing, insurance products and statement mailings. These vendors are required to treat such customer information confidentially and use the information only for the specific bank purpose stated. Vendors are prohibited from reusing or selling customer information.

We also may share certain account and customer information among the legal entities that comprise the Bank of the West family of companies. These entities may use the information to help identify additional products or services that you might want to know about.

To collect a customer's unpaid debts, we may also exchange information with financial institutions and other companies, in accordance with standard banking industry practice, to verify the existence and condition of customers' accounts.

We do not share customer information with independent companies for any other purpose without the customer's consent.

**Do you sell my information to telemarketing companies?**

We do not employ telemarketing companies to sell Bank of the West products and services, nor do we sell or give customer information to telemarketing companies to use to solicit business from you.

**May I request that you not send product information to me or share information about me with companies within the Bank of the West family?**

The law permits us to share within the Bank of the West family of companies and with credit reporting agencies information concerning a customer's account history and experiences with Bank of the West. However, if you wish to be excluded from:

(1) Offers of products or services by mail, and/or

(2) Sharing of other information about you within the Bank of the West family of companies,

Contact us at the numbers listed in the Where to Call section of the Privacy Policy.

While this may mean you might not receive product information of interest to you, we will respect your request not to receive such information by mail. (Of course, we will continue to send you routine statements and information concerning your existing accounts.)

**Protect Yourself From Fraud**

**How can I prevent financial information about me from being used fraudulently?**

Here are some suggestions:

  * Never give your credit card or bank account number to any unsolicited caller who is unknown to you and seeks to sell you something or offers you a prize.
  * Memorize your personal identification number (PIN) for ATM transactions and other banking business. If you must write it down, keep it separate from your card.
  * Never use your Social Security Number as a password.
  * Do not put your address, phone number, or other personal information that does not appear on the front of your credit card on a credit card receipt.

_Rev. April 2005_
